My name is Joshua Walters.
إسمي جوشوا والترز.
I'm a performer.
أنا فنان استعراضي.
(Beatboxing)
(إيقاعات بشرية)
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
But as far as being a performer,
لكن بقدر ما أنا فنان إستعراضي،
I'm also diagnosed
تم تشخيصي
bipolar.
كمريض بالاضطراب ثنائي القطب.
I reframe that as a positive
أعدت صياغة ذلك كأمر إيجابي،
because the crazier I get onstage,
لأنه كلما زاد جنوني على الخشبة،
the more entertaining I become.
زادت تسليتي.
When I was 16 in San Francisco,
حين كنت في 16 من عمري في سان فرانسيسكو،
I had my breakthrough manic episode
تعرضت لنوبة جنون ثورية
in which I thought I was Jesus Christ.
اعتقدت فيها أنني عيسى المسيح.
Maybe you thought that was scary,
ربما اعتقدتم أن ذلك كان مخيفا،
but actually there's no amount of drugs you can take
لكن في الواقع ليست هناك أي مقدار من المخدرات قد تأخذه
that can get you as high
ويجعلك في مستوى ثمالة
as if you think you're Jesus Christ.
أن تعتقد أنك المسيح عيسى.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I was sent to a place,
تم إرسالي إلى مكان،
a psych ward,
جناح الأمراض النفسية،
and in the psych ward,
وفي جناح الأمراض النفسية،
everyone is doing their own one-man show.
الجميع يؤدي عرضه الكوميدي الفردي.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
There's no audience like this
ليس هناك جمهور مثل هذا
to justify their rehearsal time.
لتبرير وقت البروفة.
They're just practicing.
يتدربون فقط.
One day they'll get here.
يوما ما سيصلون إلى هنا.
Now when I got out,
الآن، حين خرجت منها،
I was diagnosed
تم تشخيصي
and I was given medications
وتم إعطائي أدوية
by a psychiatrist.
من قبل طبيب نفساني.
"Okay, Josh, why don't we give you some --
"حسنا، جوش، لم لا نعطيك بعض --
why don't we give you some Zyprexa.
لم لا نعطيك بعض الزيبريكسا.
Okay? Mmhmm?
طيب؟ هممم؟
At least that's what it says on my pen."
على الأقل هذا ما هو مكتوب على قلمي."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Some of you are in the field, I can see.
بعضكم ينتمي إلى هذا المجال، أستطيع رؤية ذلك.
I can feel your noise.
أستطيع الشعور بضوضائكم.
The first half of high school
النصف الأول من المدرسة الثانوية
was the struggle of the manic episode,
كان الصراع مع النوبة الجنونية،
and the second half
والنصف الآخر
was the overmedications of these drugs,
كان التداوي الزائد بهذه العقاقير،
where I was sleeping through high school.
حين كنت نائما طوال المدرسة الثانوية.
The second half was just one big nap, pretty much, in class.
النصف الثاني كان فقط قيلولة كبيرة، إلى حد كبير، في الفصل.
When I got out
حين خرجت
I had a choice.
كان لدي خيار.
I could either deny
إما أن أتنكر
my mental illness
لمرضي العقلي
or embrace
أو أعتنق
my mental skillness.
مهارتي العقلية.
(Bugle sound)
(صوت بوق)
There's a movement going on right now
هناك حركة تشتغل حاليا
to reframe mental illness as a positive --
لإعادة صياغة المرض العقلي كأمر إيجابي --
at least the hypomanic edge part of it.
على الأقل الجزء حول حافة الهوس الخفيف منه.
Now if you don't know what hypomania is,
الآن إن لم تكونوا تعرفون ما هو الهوس الخفيف،
it's like an engine that's out of control,
إنه مثل محرك خرج عن نطاق السيطرة،
maybe a Ferrari engine, with no breaks.
ربما محرك سيارة فيراري، بدون مكابح.
Many of the speakers here, many of you in the audience,
الكثير من المتحدثين هنا، الكثير منكم في الجمهور،
have that creative edge,
لديه تلك الميزة الإبداعية،
if you know what I'm talking about.
إن كنتم تعرفون ما أتحدث عنه.
You're driven to do something
أنتم مدفوعون للقيام بشيء
that everyone has told you is impossible.
قال لكم عنه الجميع أنه مستحيل.
And there's a book -- John Gartner.
وهناك كتاب -- جون غارتنر.
John Gartner wrote this book called "The Hypomanic Edge"
جون غارتنر كتب كتابا بعنوان "ميزة الهوس الخفيف"
in which Christopher Columbus and Ted Turner and Steve Jobs
فيه كريستوفر كولمبس وتيد تورنر وستيف جوبز
and all these business minds
وكل هؤلاء الأدمغة في مجال الإقتصاد
have this edge to compete.
لديهم هذه الميزة للتنافس.
A different book was written not too long ago
كتاب مختلف كتب قبل مدة ليست بالطويلة
in the mid-90s
في منتصف التسعينيات
called "Touched With Fire" by Kay Redfield Jamison
بعنوان "ممسوس بالنار" من طرف كاي ريدفيلد جاميسون
in which it was looked at in a creative sense
وفيه تم النظر إليه في منحى إبداعي
in which Mozart and Beethoven and Van Gogh
فيه موزارت وبيتهوفن وفان غوخ
all have this manic depression that they were suffering with.
جميعا عانوا من الهوس الاكتئابي.
Some of them committed suicide.
بعضهم انتحر.
So it wasn't all
وبالتالي لم يكن دائما
the good side of the illness.
الجانب الإيجابي من المرض.
Now recently,
الآن مؤخرا،
there's been development in this field.
حصل تقدم في هذا المجال.
And there was an article written in the New York Times,
وقد كتب مقال في النيويورك تايمز،
September 2010,
سبتمبر 2010
that stated:
والذي صرح بما يلي:
"Just Manic Enough."
"مهووسا بما فيه الكفاية."
Just be manic enough
كن مهووسا بما فيه الكفاية
in which investors who are looking for entrepreneurs
وفيه المستثمرون الذي يبحثون عن أصحاب مشاريع
that have this kind of spectrum --
لديهم هذا النوع من الميزة --
you know what I'm talking about --
تعرفون ما الذي أتحدث عنه --
not maybe full bipolar,
ربما ليس اضطرابا ثنائي القطب كاملا،
but they're in the bipolar spectrum --
لكنهم في مجال الاضطراب الثنائي القطب --
where on one side,
حيث من جهة،
maybe you think you're Jesus,
قد تعتقد أنك المسيح،
and on the other side
ومن جهة أخرى
maybe they just make you a lot of money.
ربما قد يكسبك ذلك الكثير من المال.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Your call. Your call.
القرار بيدك. القرار بيدك.
And everyone's somewhere in the middle.
والجميع يوجد في مكان ما في الوسط.
Everyone's somewhere in the middle.
الجميع في مكان ما في الوسط.
So maybe, you know,
لذا ربما، تعرفون،
there's no such thing
ليس هناك شيء
as crazy,
كالجنون،
and being diagnosed with a mental illness
وكونك مشخصا بمرض عقلي
doesn't mean you're crazy.
لا يعني أنك مجنون.
But maybe it just means
لكن ربما يعني فقط
you're more sensitive
أنك أكثر حساسية
to what most people can't see
لما قد لا يراه معظم الناس
or feel.
أو يحس به.
Maybe no one's really crazy.
ربما لا أحد مجنون فعلا.
Everyone is just a little bit mad.
الجميع مخبول قليلا فقط.
How much
إلى أي درجة
depends on where you fall in the spectrum.
يعتمد على مكانك في السلم.
depends on how lucky you are.
يعتمد على مدى حظك.
Thank you.
شكرا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)